<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Just another Nodetraveller</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/</link><description>Recent content on Just another Nodetraveller</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Copyright 2007-{year} Lawrence Carvalho. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.nodetraveller.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My javascript testing toolchain</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/My-javascript-testing-toolchain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/My-javascript-testing-toolchain/</guid><description>Update (Jan 4th 2014): Since I wrote this post, I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to using Karma instead of testem. Karma is written and supported by the Angular guys and in the year or so since this post was originally written has matured more than testem. I have a karma skeleton project that I use to setup my frontend testing environment. The readme for that project is pretty extensive and outlines how to set up a karma project.</description></item><item><title>Creating js files with Rhino (from JSON)</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/creating-js-files-with-rhino-from-json/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 23:41:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/creating-js-files-with-rhino-from-json/</guid><description>(This is primarily a note to myself)
I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with Rhino. Specifically, reading in json objects, turning that into normal, runnable objects and saving that to a file so browsers can run it. More specifically, the code that transforms the JSON to an object in the browser should be exactly the same as the one that runs in Rhino. That way I don&amp;rsquo;t have to maintain two different versions.</description></item><item><title>ActsAsUndoable</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/actasundo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 09:04:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/actasundo/</guid><description>With web apps becoming more and more like Desktop apps, it seems like user interfaces need be more like desktop user interfaces too. Some of these web apps can have a complex UI and their users need to be able to feel comfortable with it. Of course, making the UI as simple as possible is key, but if a task is relatively complex then the UI will also be relatively complex.</description></item><item><title>AjaxEvent</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/ajaxevent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 21:25:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/ajaxevent/</guid><description>Tim Huegdon has a great post about a really rather sweet piece of code called AjaxEvent over at his site, nefariousdesigns. Developed with Mark Aidan Thomas, AjaxEvent is an object that wraps around the YUI Connection and CustomEvents that makes managing multiple, distinct ajax calls really easy.</description></item><item><title>Another Tabbed Interface</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/another-tabbed-interface/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2007 21:15:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/another-tabbed-interface/</guid><description>This is a rather belated post and is sort of a continuation of my last post about Aspect Oriented Programming. I&amp;rsquo;ve made yet another tabbed interface widgety thing (like the &amp;lsquo;tubes needs another one) that uses AOP to add additonal features. A tabbed interface widget provided a nice problem for me to experiment with AOP. You can see the results which allows tabs in a widget to be draggable and closeable too.</description></item><item><title>JS Fun</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/js-fun/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2007 20:01:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/js-fun/</guid><description>For the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with different design patterns and methodologies in Javascript. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at the Composite pattern and also Aspects Oriented Programming (AOP).
AOP is a way of changing the behaviour of existing code without modifying it. It does this by providing, what AOP calls, advice at certain join points. In plain english, it provides a way of adding additional behaviour (advice) at certain points in your program (join points).</description></item><item><title>Howdy..</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/howdy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2006 12:01:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/howdy/</guid><description>Hey.
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while.
Been busy with work, life and stuff.
But feel like posting again so I&amp;rsquo;ve changed servers and got a temp design up, which will change soon.
So let&amp;rsquo;s see what happens.</description></item><item><title>Another LiveInfo fix</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/another-liveinfo-fix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2005 20:57:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/another-liveinfo-fix/</guid><description>Andrew Gregory reported some bugs in Opera 7.54u2. The bug in Opera 7.54u2 turned out to be rather strange. Any opera browser below 7.6 uses an iframe and I check the html within the frame to see if it is loaded. I use the text as that is the root node. In 7.54u2, there is no , only . Strange. Anyway I introduced a check for that and it works okay now.</description></item><item><title>LiveInfo Update</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 18:48:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-update/</guid><description>Just a minor update release on LiveInfo. Version 1.01 just tidies up some Javascript warnings that sometimes occur.</description></item><item><title>Semantic Web - right now</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/semantic-web-right-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2005 14:25:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/semantic-web-right-now/</guid><description>A semantic interface means finding information online will be much easier as unrelated results won&amp;rsquo;t appear. Here&amp;rsquo;s a gentle intro to the semantic web.
The semantic web won&amp;rsquo;t be in wide use yet but the University of Southhampton has released an interface to a new semantic web interface called mSpace. They have an example interface searching for classical music which currently is Mozilla only. It is javascript driven and uses xmlhttprequest to retrieve the data.</description></item><item><title>Introducing LiveInfo..</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/introducing-liveinfo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 15:46:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/introducing-liveinfo/</guid><description>Directly evolved from liveSearch, is a updated version which I&amp;rsquo;m calling liveInfo. As can be seen at chregu&amp;rsquo;s blog LiveSearch displays live search results while a user enters the search text. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen Google Suggest which uses the same technology (XMLHTTPRequest).
One of the coolest things about liveSearch is the keyboard navigation where users, when the input field has the focus, the user can navigate through the results using the up and down keys on the keyboard.</description></item><item><title>LiveInfo - How it works</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-how-it-works/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 15:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-how-it-works/</guid><description>LiveInfo is directly evolved from Livesearch. If you don’t know what liveSearch is, liveSearch allowed users to search a website while still viewing the current page. The original can be seen here. Wanting to make use of liveSearch for one of my own projects, I proceeded to make some changes from which evolved LiveInfo. LiveInfo is a framework for multiple, real time, skinnable updatable elements within a web page. You can see LiveInfo in action on my blog where there are two LiveInfo elements.</description></item><item><title>Unobstrusive Javascript</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/unobstrusive-javascript/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2005 16:30:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/unobstrusive-javascript/</guid><description>An excellent article with examples of the correct way to do javascript.</description></item><item><title>A change...</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/a-change/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2005 21:44:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/a-change/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve moved my blog from Mambo to Wordpress. Mambo is a great CMS but as a blogging tool, its not quite so mature. I wanted something simple and web standards friendly and wordpress seems to be it. The casualties in this move are the comments and the uk tv guide. I&amp;rsquo;m no longer publishing the component as its a Mambo component. but head on over to SynTV for the listings. Fortunately I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged too much over and I was able to transfer over by good old cut n paste.</description></item><item><title>SynTV - Public Beta</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/syntv-public-beta/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2004 16:20:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/syntv-public-beta/</guid><description>My latest project www.syntv.com is just about finished and is now out on a public beta.
SynTV provides UK TV listings in syndication formats (RSS 2.0 and ATOM) for use with desktop feed aggregators. Users can generate their own specific categories and searches and site developers are also provided for with support for HTML and Javascript. In a couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ll also publish the XMLRPC web service.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, please check it out and give me some feedback&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>UK TV Listings via XMLRPC</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-listings-via-xmlrpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2004 20:58:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-listings-via-xmlrpc/</guid><description>The UK TV Guide for Mambo component is basically a XML RPC client thats talks to the XML RPC server here at nodetraveller.com and renders the data it gets back in a nice way. The component has been released for a few weeks now and I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been using the service for a long time before that too so its probably a good time to let people know how to access it&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>RSS options in Mambo</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/rss-options-in-mambo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2004 14:29:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/rss-options-in-mambo/</guid><description>I was a bit disappointed with the standard rss feature in Mambo as it only supports rss 0.91. Suprisingly, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a component available that outputs the content in any of the other formats so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go. No point in reinventing the wheel so I made use of an excellent class called FeedCreator. It can output in RSS 0.91, 1.0 and 2.0 as well as OPML and ATOM 0.</description></item><item><title> UK TV Guide Component</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-component/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2004 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-component/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just completed a component for Mambo. As you can probably guess by the name, it retreives and displays the TV and Radio listings for the UK. At the moment, there is a choice of over 60 channels and two ways of displaying the listings; columns and timeline.
I spent a bit more time on the UI than normal but finally I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with it. It works using XML RPC, connecting to my service and then displaying the listings.</description></item><item><title>I'm back!</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/im-back/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2004 16:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/im-back/</guid><description>I knew I hadn&amp;rsquo;t posted in a while but I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 3 months! What have I been up to?!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of work with Mambo recently and I like the thing so much I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be moving the backend of this blog form Movable Type to Mambo. The main reason for this is that I&amp;rsquo;ll need to put up a version of Mambo up anyway to demo the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, so I might as well use it to blog as well.</description></item><item><title> Get your dancing shoes on..</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/get-your-dancing-shoes-on/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2004 15:06:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/get-your-dancing-shoes-on/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using an opensource CMS application recently called Mambo.
We needed some kind of CMS for our own site and after looking around, weren&amp;rsquo;t really happy with what was out there..
The sites based on *nuke seem so chaotic. But not Mambo. The sites created with Mambo are nicely designed and user friendly. But the admin interface is absolutely brilliant! Its a well designed system with a great community. Theres quite a few templates around which quite nice to look at.</description></item><item><title> It's been a while...</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/its-been-a-while/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2004 16:24:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/its-been-a-while/</guid><description>..since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted. I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with a couple of projects and haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time. These projects were Java and PHP based with pure HTML frontends but could probably be enhanced quite nicely if using Flash. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably add this to my list of things to do with Flash. Lately this list of mine is getting longer; either my creative think tank juices are overflowing or there&amp;rsquo;s never enough time.</description></item><item><title>Usability for RIAs</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/usability-for-rias/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2003 16:26:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/usability-for-rias/</guid><description>This may be a few months old but I only just discovered it. This article discusses Jakobs Nielsen 1994 usability heuristics for desktop applications with respect to Rich Internet Applications. Most of us might be used to website heuristics but RIAs are more like desktop applications and should be treated similarly and the article explains how.</description></item><item><title>A nice surprise...</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/a-nice-surprise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2003 16:28:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/a-nice-surprise/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit busy over the last week or so and haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to do post anything or even read ppls blogs. But I had a rather pleasant surprise when I caught up on my reading and found Mario Klingmann at Quasimondo had mentioned this site on his blog! Very nice indeed! Thanks Mario&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;ve got a few flash projects in the pipeline that I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to find the time to work on.</description></item><item><title> RSS in Flash 2004</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/rss-in-flash-2004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2003 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/rss-in-flash-2004/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to post anything recently but I have had time to quickly cobble together a little app using flash 2004 and its components. Yet another rss app but it shows nicely the usage of various components, old and new, that 2004 offers.
It uses the Accordion and TextArea UIComponents and the XMLConnector to load the urls of the feeds to download. Flash&amp;rsquo;s css support is also demostrated within the textarea.</description></item><item><title>Design Patterns in Flash</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/design-patterns-in-flash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2003 17:20:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/design-patterns-in-flash/</guid><description>Now Actionscript is OO, I thought it would be useful to try out implementing a design pattern in Flash. The pattern I chose is the Memento pattern, which is mainly used to implement &amp;ldquo;undo&amp;rdquo; functionality in applications. The reason I chose Memento is because its a pattern that uses interfaces and I wanted to explore this in AS 2.0. An interface is an object that defines methods but has no implementation.</description></item><item><title> Flash TvGuide App</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-tvguide-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2003 14:53:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-tvguide-app/</guid><description>Okay, heres the flash client (only 47k!) for the TVguide webservice posted recently.
It&amp;rsquo;s quite a fairly simple movie using flash remoting and amfphp. I used amf to call my tvguide webservice via SOAP. Instead of having your swf call a specifc flash service, you call a special service which acts like a proxy to SOAP webservices. This service looks like this..
1// AMFPHP uses by default the PEAR::SOAP 2// library, so you need to define in the 3// gateway not to use that.</description></item><item><title> UK TV Guide Webservice</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-webservice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 15:08:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-webservice/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a webservice using PHP and nusoap. It provides information about 41 UK TV and radio programming schedule for the upcoming week.
The wsdl can be found here and example php client here.
I&amp;rsquo;m just finishing the final touches to a flash client which I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting sometime within the next couple days. Hopefully this will show how to use the webservice in your flash apps..</description></item><item><title>Webservices in Flash 2004</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/webservices-in-flash-2004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 18:10:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/webservices-in-flash-2004/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing about with the webservice connector in flash mx 2004. What I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered is that connecting to a webservice and using the data returned is really easy.
I&amp;rsquo;m using the tvGuide webservice (http://www.nodetraveller.com/webservices/tvGuide/tvGuideService.php?wsdl here at nodetraveller.com as one of the operations it provides is a list of channels which would look ideal in a listbox.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide to using a webservice:
Create a new document from a Query-Error-Response template.</description></item><item><title>Old Stock....</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/old-stock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 16:46:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/old-stock/</guid><description>Looking through the cobwebs of my old laptop backups,I (re)discovered my old DHTML newsfeeds mini-app. This app lists all newsfeeds from moreover.com and provides a user interface to view the feeds and store favourite feeds and it does this without reloading the whole pages so it can be a component within a page rather than a page in itself. You can see it here or download here.
It loads the data via javascript though I did have an xml version but that one didn&amp;rsquo;t survive&amp;hellip;In fact I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much longer moreover.</description></item><item><title> Flash 2004</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-2004/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2003 16:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-2004/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s here! well, almost anyway&amp;hellip;
Flash 2004 will be released next month. I know, I&amp;rsquo;m a few days behind but I&amp;rsquo;ve been too busy to post and besides this blog didn&amp;rsquo;t exist when the word came out so I have probably the best excuse in the world for a late blog about F2004.
Anyway though I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy, I have been able to read up on the new features of flash.</description></item><item><title>A new node is born...</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/a-new-node-is-born/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2003 16:41:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/a-new-node-is-born/</guid><description>and you&amp;rsquo;re reading its first blog. Which is nice, for me at least.
Why have I got a blog? Well, it allows me to put up anything I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on and to comment on anything I feel like commenting on&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t have a great big message or anything like that for people. It&amp;rsquo;s just another blog from just another bloke..</description></item></channel></rss>