<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Webservices on Just another Nodetraveller</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/tags/Webservices/</link><description>Recent content in Webservices on Just another Nodetraveller</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Copyright 2007-{year} Lawrence Carvalho. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 15:46:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nodetraveller.com/tags/Webservices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing LiveInfo..</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/introducing-liveinfo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 15:46:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/introducing-liveinfo/</guid><description>Directly evolved from liveSearch, is a updated version which I&amp;rsquo;m calling liveInfo. As can be seen at chregu&amp;rsquo;s blog LiveSearch displays live search results while a user enters the search text. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen Google Suggest which uses the same technology (XMLHTTPRequest).
One of the coolest things about liveSearch is the keyboard navigation where users, when the input field has the focus, the user can navigate through the results using the up and down keys on the keyboard.</description></item><item><title>UK TV Listings via XMLRPC</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-listings-via-xmlrpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2004 20:58:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-listings-via-xmlrpc/</guid><description>The UK TV Guide for Mambo component is basically a XML RPC client thats talks to the XML RPC server here at nodetraveller.com and renders the data it gets back in a nice way. The component has been released for a few weeks now and I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been using the service for a long time before that too so its probably a good time to let people know how to access it&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title> UK TV Guide Component</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-component/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2004 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-component/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just completed a component for Mambo. As you can probably guess by the name, it retreives and displays the TV and Radio listings for the UK. At the moment, there is a choice of over 60 channels and two ways of displaying the listings; columns and timeline.
I spent a bit more time on the UI than normal but finally I&amp;rsquo;m pleased with it. It works using XML RPC, connecting to my service and then displaying the listings.</description></item><item><title> Flash TvGuide App</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-tvguide-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2003 14:53:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-tvguide-app/</guid><description>Okay, heres the flash client (only 47k!) for the TVguide webservice posted recently.
It&amp;rsquo;s quite a fairly simple movie using flash remoting and amfphp. I used amf to call my tvguide webservice via SOAP. Instead of having your swf call a specifc flash service, you call a special service which acts like a proxy to SOAP webservices. This service looks like this..
1// AMFPHP uses by default the PEAR::SOAP 2// library, so you need to define in the 3// gateway not to use that.</description></item><item><title> UK TV Guide Webservice</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-webservice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 15:08:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-webservice/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a webservice using PHP and nusoap. It provides information about 41 UK TV and radio programming schedule for the upcoming week.
The wsdl can be found here and example php client here.
I&amp;rsquo;m just finishing the final touches to a flash client which I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting sometime within the next couple days. Hopefully this will show how to use the webservice in your flash apps..</description></item></channel></rss>