<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>liveinfo on Just another Nodetraveller</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/tags/liveinfo/</link><description>Recent content in liveinfo on Just another Nodetraveller</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Copyright 2007-{year} Lawrence Carvalho. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2005 20:57:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.nodetraveller.com/tags/liveinfo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Another LiveInfo fix</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/another-liveinfo-fix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2005 20:57:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/another-liveinfo-fix/</guid><description>Andrew Gregory reported some bugs in Opera 7.54u2. The bug in Opera 7.54u2 turned out to be rather strange. Any opera browser below 7.6 uses an iframe and I check the html within the frame to see if it is loaded. I use the text as that is the root node. In 7.54u2, there is no , only . Strange. Anyway I introduced a check for that and it works okay now.</description></item><item><title>LiveInfo Update</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2005 18:48:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-update/</guid><description>Just a minor update release on LiveInfo. Version 1.01 just tidies up some Javascript warnings that sometimes occur.</description></item><item><title>Introducing LiveInfo..</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/introducing-liveinfo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 15:46:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/introducing-liveinfo/</guid><description>Directly evolved from liveSearch, is a updated version which I&amp;rsquo;m calling liveInfo. As can be seen at chregu&amp;rsquo;s blog LiveSearch displays live search results while a user enters the search text. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen Google Suggest which uses the same technology (XMLHTTPRequest).
One of the coolest things about liveSearch is the keyboard navigation where users, when the input field has the focus, the user can navigate through the results using the up and down keys on the keyboard.</description></item><item><title>LiveInfo - How it works</title><link>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-how-it-works/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2005 15:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/liveinfo-how-it-works/</guid><description>LiveInfo is directly evolved from Livesearch. If you don’t know what liveSearch is, liveSearch allowed users to search a website while still viewing the current page. The original can be seen here. Wanting to make use of liveSearch for one of my own projects, I proceeded to make some changes from which evolved LiveInfo. LiveInfo is a framework for multiple, real time, skinnable updatable elements within a web page. You can see LiveInfo in action on my blog where there are two LiveInfo elements.</description></item></channel></rss>