<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flash on Just another Nodetraveller</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/tags/Flash/</link><description>Recent content in Flash on Just another Nodetraveller</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><copyright>Copyright 2007-{year} Lawrence Carvalho. All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2003 17:10:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.nodetraveller.com/tags/Flash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title> RSS in Flash 2004</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/rss-in-flash-2004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2003 17:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/rss-in-flash-2004/</guid><description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t had time to post anything recently but I have had time to quickly cobble together a little app using flash 2004 and its components. Yet another rss app but it shows nicely the usage of various components, old and new, that 2004 offers.
It uses the Accordion and TextArea UIComponents and the XMLConnector to load the urls of the feeds to download. Flash&amp;rsquo;s css support is also demostrated within the textarea.</description></item><item><title>Design Patterns in Flash</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/design-patterns-in-flash/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2003 17:20:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/design-patterns-in-flash/</guid><description>Now Actionscript is OO, I thought it would be useful to try out implementing a design pattern in Flash. The pattern I chose is the Memento pattern, which is mainly used to implement &amp;ldquo;undo&amp;rdquo; functionality in applications. The reason I chose Memento is because its a pattern that uses interfaces and I wanted to explore this in AS 2.0. An interface is an object that defines methods but has no implementation.</description></item><item><title> Flash TvGuide App</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-tvguide-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2003 14:53:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-tvguide-app/</guid><description>Okay, heres the flash client (only 47k!) for the TVguide webservice posted recently.
It&amp;rsquo;s quite a fairly simple movie using flash remoting and amfphp. I used amf to call my tvguide webservice via SOAP. Instead of having your swf call a specifc flash service, you call a special service which acts like a proxy to SOAP webservices. This service looks like this..
1// AMFPHP uses by default the PEAR::SOAP 2// library, so you need to define in the 3// gateway not to use that.</description></item><item><title> UK TV Guide Webservice</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-webservice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2003 15:08:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/uk-tv-guide-webservice/</guid><description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a webservice using PHP and nusoap. It provides information about 41 UK TV and radio programming schedule for the upcoming week.
The wsdl can be found here and example php client here.
I&amp;rsquo;m just finishing the final touches to a flash client which I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting sometime within the next couple days. Hopefully this will show how to use the webservice in your flash apps..</description></item><item><title>Webservices in Flash 2004</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/webservices-in-flash-2004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 18:10:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/webservices-in-flash-2004/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing about with the webservice connector in flash mx 2004. What I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered is that connecting to a webservice and using the data returned is really easy.
I&amp;rsquo;m using the tvGuide webservice (http://www.nodetraveller.com/webservices/tvGuide/tvGuideService.php?wsdl here at nodetraveller.com as one of the operations it provides is a list of channels which would look ideal in a listbox.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick guide to using a webservice:
Create a new document from a Query-Error-Response template.</description></item><item><title> Flash 2004</title><link>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-2004/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2003 16:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.nodetraveller.com/post/source/flash-2004/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s here! well, almost anyway&amp;hellip;
Flash 2004 will be released next month. I know, I&amp;rsquo;m a few days behind but I&amp;rsquo;ve been too busy to post and besides this blog didn&amp;rsquo;t exist when the word came out so I have probably the best excuse in the world for a late blog about F2004.
Anyway though I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy, I have been able to read up on the new features of flash.</description></item></channel></rss>